Richard CSAKY

- richard.csaky@psych.ox.ac.uk
- ricsinaruto.github.io
- o github.com/ricsinaruto
- scholar.google

I have obtained my **PhD** at **Oxford**, where I gained expertise in collecting, analyzing, and **decoding non-invasive brain** data using novel **deep learning** approaches. My background is in robotics and computer science, along with **3 years** of applied machine learning **experience** in **computer vision** and **language** processing. I have a particular interest in **speech** BCI applications and emerging **BCI technologies**.

EDUCATION)

PhD in Machine Learning and Neuroscience

Secured \$100,000 studentship.

Presented research at 4 international conferences. Authored 2 publications on novel deep learning methods for modeling and decoding brain activity. Designed reading and inner speech experiments, running 30+ EEG, MEG, MRI, OPM sessions. Built a closed-loop EMG silent speech interface. Wrote over 10,000 lines of code in Python for data analysis, signal processing, and machine learning. Led 5-person team in a hackathon with a BCI idea.

University of Oxford ♥

2020 - 2023

M.S. in Computer Science Engineering

Attended courses (BCI, bioinformatics, neural networks) at KU Leuven (Belgium) for 1 semester.

Awarded the National Excellence Scholarship.

Attended EEML (machine learning summer school).

Presented research at 6 conferences and meetups.

Budapest University of Technology (Hungary)

2018 - 2020

B.S. in Mechatronics Engineering

Implemented molecular circuit simulation platform in C++, winning 2nd place at university conference. Budapest University of Technology (Hungary) ♥

2014 - 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Actively using

- EEG/MEG experiment design and execution
- Python, PyTorch Git LaTex Matlab
 - Signal processing

Studied and self-taught, used in projects

- Java/Android C/C++/C# OpenGL
 - TensorFlow Inventor, LabView, Ansys

EXPERIENCE

Computational Neuroscientist

Developing machine learning methods for analyzing and decoding multichannel electrophysiology data.

- **♦** Sonera (Remote)
- **昔** February 2024 − present

Scientific Consultant

- 1. BCI startup (Technical Specialist, Apr. 2023 p) Providing guidance for a BCI prototype, focusing on ML algorithms for user experience and accuracy.
- 2. Sonera (July 2023 December 2023)
- 3. Chatbot startup (June 2020 August 2020)
- **♥** Various
- **±** 2020 present

Natural Language Processing Researcher

- 1. Led dialog modelling research, publishing a novel data-filtering method at ACL, and winning a national competition with a review of 150 papers
- 2. Developed one of the first Transformer-based chatbots, with over 400 stars on GitHub
- 3. Created and published a new dataset at EACL
- 4. Developed online GPT2 chatbot used by 100s
- 5. Mentored students on NLP projects (1, 2, 3, 4)
- Budapest University of Technology (Hungary)
- **昔** February 2018 − October 2019

Software Engineer

Built a UI for real-time manipulation of parking spots on camera feed. Adapted YOLO for parking space segmentation, achieving results that led to the allocation of a dedicated team and funding.

- **♦** Bosch (Hungary)
- **July 2017 August 2018**

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership Adaptable Problem-solving
- Cross-functional Communicator (Podcast)